Contact

bethanynue@gmail.com

www.linkedin.com/in/bethanynue (LinkedIn)

Top Skills

Product Design
Design Systems
Figma (Software)

Bethany Nuechterlein

Product Designer

Los Angeles, California, United States

Summary

I'm a product designer with over a decade of experience designing web and mobile apps. As a lifelong puzzle enthusiast, I love tackling complex problems, whether that's creating an intuitive interface for a complex workflow or a scalable design system.

Want to learn more? Check out the about page on my website bethany.io/about

Experience

Self-employed Product Designer August 2021 - Present (3 years 4 months) Los Angeles, CA

I founded, designed, and built Scout, a tool to help people find natural wine. I also

co-founded and designed Pop-in, a mobile app that helps friends meet up in real life, and designed and built web and mobile projects for HBO and other clients.

Lumi

6 years

Lead Product Designer

August 2019 - August 2021 (2 years 1 month)

Los Angeles, CA

I designed a multi-platform marketplace that connects e-commerce brands with

packaging manufacturers. This work reduced the average quote request response time by 50% and the average sales hours per client by 40%. I also built a new design system using Figma and created a design system wiki.

As a design leader, I interviewed and onboarded new design hires, led weekly design review sessions, and mentored junior designers. I was also an integral

member of our small product team, developing feature requirements and using data to advocate for features that would improve our clients' experience.

Senior Product Designer

May 2017 - August 2019 (2 years 4 months)

Los Angeles, CA

I designed an internal tool for managing orders, quotes, and shipments. I also created a quote request flow and built a design system using Sketch.

Founding Product Designer

September 2015 - May 2017 (1 year 9 months)

Los Angeles, CA

I designed a platform for creating and ordering custom packaging, a marketing site, and brand collateral.

Slate Studio

Interactive Designer

September 2014 - September 2015 (1 year 1 month)

Venice, CA

I designed a fitness streaming app for Lionsgate, a mobile app for an aeronautics startup, and a CMS tool. Other clients included Tribeca, Oracle, and Machinima.

Freelance

Interactive Designer

August 2013 - September 2014 (1 year 2 months)

Los Angeles, CA

I designed an online store for a women's clothing retailer and designed and built websites for shows on IFC and Comedy Central.

Sprocket House

Web Designer

August 2012 - August 2013 (1 year 1 month)

Carrboro, NC

I designed websites, branding, and collateral for small businesses. Clients included a non-profit, an energy company, a restaurant, a distillery, and a production company.

ReverbNation

Web Designer

June 2011 - August 2012 (1 year 3 months)

Durham, NC

I was the sole designer responsible for the UI/UX of a music networking platform. I designed a band profile page, a music player, and other features.

Viget Labs
Web Design Intern
January 2011 - April 2011 (4 months)
Durham, NC

I designed websites for a local architecture firm and a non-profit. I learned how to lead an effective design process from UX to high-fidelity designs.

Education

University of North Carolina at Chapel Hill
Bachelor of Arts, Design and Visual Communications · (August 2006 - May 2010)